A Guide to the Marching Virginians' April 16, 2007 Condolence Collection, 2007
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Marching Virginians' April 16, 2007 Condolence Collection, 2007
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2013-084
3.0 cu. ft. 5 boxes
The collection contains the condolence materials received by the Marching Virginians after April 16, 2007. Much of the material pertains to Ryan "Stack" Christopher Clark, baritone and student leader in the Marching Virginians. This collection incorporates a variety of materials and artifacts, including correspondence, posters, banners, an American flag flown on the USS Constitution, scrapbooks, and a band uniform.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Marching Virginians' April 16, 2007 Condolence Collection was donated to Special Collections in 2011.
Biographical and Historical Notes
Historical Note
Formed in 1974, the Marching Virginians are one of Virginia Tech's two university marching bands. On April 16, 2007, the Marching Virginians lost one of their baritone players and band leaders, Ryan "Stack" Clark, in an attack on the Virginia Tech campus that took the lives of 27 students and five members of the faculty and staff. In the following days and months, the Marching Virginians received an outpouring of condolence letters and items from Marching Virginian alumni and bands from various institutions expressing their sympathy and solidarity.
Biographical Note
Ryan "Stack" Christopher Clark (1984-2007) was born in Landstuhl, West Germany. He attended Virginia Tech, majoring in Psychology, Biology, and English. Clark was a member of the Marching Virginians, Virginia Tech's university band, where he played the baritone. He was also a student leader on campus and served as resident advisor in West Ambler Johnston Hall.
For more biographical information refer to the following: http://www.weremember.vt.edu/biographies/clark.html
Scope and Content
The collection contains the condolence materials received by the Marching Virginians after April 16, 2007. Much of the material pertains to Ryan "Stack" Christopher Clark, baritone and student leader in the Marching Virginians. This collection incorporates a variety of materials and artifacts, including correspondence, posters, banners, an American flag flown on the USS Constitution, scrapbooks, and a band uniform. Many of the materials were sent to the Marching Virginians from other bands and are signed by band members from these various institutions.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
Virginia Tech April 16, 2007 Archives of the University Libraries, 2007-2010. Ms2008-020. Finding aid available online.
April 16, 2007, Condolence Archives. Collection of digital images available online.
Index Terms
Subjects:
April 16, 2007 shootings; University Archives; University History; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
- Papers
  - Newspaper Clippings, 2007 (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Memorial Service for Ryan Christopher Clark, 2007 (Box-folder 1-2)
  - Alumni, 2007 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Army Bands, 2007 (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Business, 2007 (Box-folder 1-5)
  - City and Community Bands, 2007 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Individuals and Groups of Individuals, 2007 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Religious Group, 2007 (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Middle Schools, 2007 (Box-folder 1-9)
  - High Schools, 2007 (Box-folder 1-10)
  - Colleges and Universities, 2007 (Box-folder 1-11)
  - University of Minnesota Marching Band, 2007 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Artifacts
  - American Flag Flown Onboard the USS Constitution (Box 2)
  - United States Ship Constitution Framed Condolence Letter (Box 2)
  - Signed Wake Forest University Band Uniform (Box 2)
  - Ryan "Stack" Clark Memorial Banner (Box 2)
  - Signed Drum Head (Box 3)
  - "Friendship" Book from the Florida State Marching Chiefs, 2007 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook from the UVA Cavalier Marching Band (Box 3)
  - University of Minnesota Gopher Bobblehead (Box 3)
  - Signed Paper Banner from Tau Beta Sigma and Kappa Kappa Psi, Razorback Band (Box 4)
  - Signed Poster from the Marquette University Band (Box 4)
  - Signed Posters and Oversized Condolence Cards from Various Bands (Box-folder 5-1)